# A.N.Abishek

No.14, N.S.K Nagar, (1st Street, Bashyam Nagar), Chromepet, Chennai, India.

+91-7200483919 | anabishek@gmail.com | Github - AbishekNavukkarasan | Linkedin - AbishekNavukkarasan

### **Professional summary**

A Passionate Interdisciplinary engineer with 2 Years of in-depth experience in Open Source development for Tech Startups. I design, make, weld, fabricate, solder and code. Looking for a challenging career which demands the best of my technical and analytical skills, and helps me in broadening and enhancing my current skills and knowledge.

### **Experience**

### **R&D Intern / Lema Labs Technologies Pvt. Ltd.**

December 2017 - Present, Chennai

Develop and design Robotic kits from concept and proof of principles to specifications and implementation. Coordinate with internal or external engineering teams on new designs and capability improvement and validation.

**Project Intern** / RapidFab 3D Engineering Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

January 2018 - May 2018, Chennai

Development of SCARA Robotic arm 3D Printer; working from initial concept and design to production phase, machining, prototyping, testing, and release.

### **Team Lead / Team Algol**

August 2016 - December 2016, Chennai

Led a cross-functional engineering team in the design and implementation of a precision device capable of identifying the existence of life on the lunar surface.

### **R&D Hardware Intern / Rent&Make Virtual Makerspace**

July 2016 - December 2016, Chennai

Researched, Designed, Developed and Optimised Open source hardware. Was responsible for managing and deployment of 4 major products to customers. Created and managed fabrication budgets and operating specifications.

#### Courses

### Kaizen Robotics Program / Lema Labs Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

July - August 2016, Chennai

Robotics development using embedded C.

CAD Using CATIA / AU-FRG Institute for CAD/CAM, Anna University

December 2015, Chennai

A Computer-aided Designing course using CATIA.

#### **Education**

### **B.E**, Mechanical Engineering / Anna University

6.55 CGPA - August 2014 - May 2018

**Higher Sec. Certificate** / Zion Matriculation Higher Sec. School

66.75% - March 2014 - Selaiyur, Chennai

**Secondary School Certificate** / Zion Matriculation School

79.2% - April 2012 - Sembakkam, Chennai

### Skills:

### **Design and Analysis:**

Dassault Systèmes: CATIA. SolidWorks AutoDesk: AutoCAD, Fusion 360

Analysis:

Simscale, Ansys

### **Programming Language:**

Python: Basic C: Basic

Embedded C: Intermediate

Document Management:

- MS Office (Word, Powerpoint, Excel)
- Google Docs, Sheets, Slides

### **Projects:**

#### **SCARA Robotic Arm 3D Printer**

Final Year Project December 2017 - May 2018, Chennai

#### Lab2Moon

Team Algol/Team Indus August 2016 - December 2016, Chennai

### **Autonomous Tractor**

Autodesk India Design Week November 2017 - December 2017, Chenna

### Improvised Prusa i3 3D Printer

Design and Fabrication Project December 2016 - March 2017, Chennai

#### **Areas of Interest:**

- ★ Robotics
- ★ Machine Learning
- ★ Internet of Things
- ★ 3D Printing
- ★ Space technologies

## **Extra-Curriculars:**

- NCC "C" Certified as of September 2017
- Student Ambassador of Kurukshetra 2k17
- Participated and Won prizes in several National level Symposiums and Student Conventions.
- Public Relations Head and Web Developer Mars2k17. 19th National Level symposium conducted by the Department of Mechanical engineering, Sri Sairam Engineering College.
- Active Participation in Workshops and meetups of Local online communities, related to IoT, 3D Printing, Makerspace, AI/Machine learning.
- Was one of the finalists of Autodesk India Design week 2017 competition.

#### Personal Details:

DOB: 19-08-1996 Languages: English, Tamil.